# Robert Phillips

## Full Stack Web Developer



Industrial & systems engineer turned full stack developer with a tenacity for solving problems in the people business. With 20 years of varied professional work experience, this blend has produced an ability to collaborate in widely diverse environments both technically and culturally. Looking to partner with a company to develop technical solutions and optimize and improve existing systems.

## **Technical Skills**

- Ruby on Rails, ActiveRecord, BCrypt and JWT authentication, RESTful routing standard practices
- React Javascript framework including Redux, and client-side routing
- > CSS (Bootstrap, Material UI), HTML, Styled Components
- PostgreSQL, SQLite3, Airtable

#### Projects

#### Acuity PPM (https://acuityppm.com - GitHub repo (private))

Project Portfolio Management web application for business executive operations management

- > Rails, ReactJS, Redux, Auth0, SyncFusion, Immutable.js, React Bootstrap, i18next translation
- Styled with React Bootstrap / SCSS for elegant design and UX

## Babysitter [GitHub FrontEnd] | [GitHub BackEnd] | [Demo]

An app to help parents and babysitters to browse for and find one another

- Rails API server with React/Redux Javascript front end with client side routing.
- Styled with React Bootstrap and Styled Components.
- FullCalender.io API for job scheduling interface. Bcrypt and JSON Web Token encryption for user auth and security.

## Dispatch [GitHub FrontEnd] | [GitHub BackEnd] | [Demo]

A map-based app for assigning working and dispatching service professionals

- Currently in use by local hospice to optimally assign patients to employees and manage/track job progress.
- Uses Mapbox API to optimize service dispatch leveraging physical locations of providers, patients
- > Rails API server back end with React JavaScript front end using Material UI react components

## **Professional Experience**

#### **Full Stack Software Developer**

Acuity PPM & Lencomms | 2020 - Present

- Lencomms dev consultant to Acuity Project Portfolio Management (PPM)
- > Develop & maintain comprehensive Acuity PPM web application product
- > Tech employed: Rails, ReactJS, Redux, AuthO, SyncFusion, Immutable.js, React Bootstrap, Spanish

#### Director of Campus Ministry (Christian Students GT & Christian Students UGA)

Church in Atlanta/Athens | 2009 - Present

- > Technical: Website, social media, brand mgt. Event planning, online registration, app development.
- > Daily oversight of local campus team (avg. 10) + coordination at regional/national level (avg. 300)
- Counseling, teaching, & development of team members and students including conflict resolution

#### Sales engineer / Account manager

The Trane Company | 2002 - 2007

Managed multiple contractor, engineering, and property owner accounts competitively bidding, winning, and fulfilling commercial construction contracts such as \$2 million Gwinnett schools WSHP sole-source contract

#### Education

Flatiron School	(Full stack web development leveraging Ruby on Rails & React JS - 2020)
Full-Time Training Anaheim	(Bible truth and church service training - 2009)
Georgia Institute of Technology	(BS Industrial & Systems Engineering - 2001)